After this period of study,
we now understand that much of combinatorics is counting.
its goals are
twofold.
Nothing should be repeated or missed.
In fact counting is not as simple as we'd all like to think,
because of the sheer size of the dataset we're facing.
Moreover, the elements of the dataset have complex relations.
So to count well, to study combinatorics well,
we require some skill with abstraction.
Some of the methods used in combinatorics are not all that deep,
but some brilliant ideas involved allow us to logically partition cases.
We need to grasp how to change our perspective.
So combinatorics is indeed a very attractive field.