I think we've all thought about it long and hard.
How did you arrive at your answer?
Suppose we want to have all the nations of the world
participating in the World Cup elimination stage.
So if there are 224 teams proceeding to the elimination stage,
how many matches will be played?
So how did everyone
solve the quiz problem?
Perhaps you drew a very complicated decision tree,
and counted up all the nodes to find out the solution.
If there are now 224 nations in the knockout matches,
will you still count like this?
How large must your decision tree be?
Is there a better way?
Let's try to get to the solution quickly.
If we reconsider the problem,
it's actually saying that in every match,
there has to be a winner and a loser,
with the loser being eliminated. How many ultimately remain?
Only the champion is left standing.
Every match corresponds to an eliminated team.
So the number of teams eliminated
is equal to the number of matches!
If out of 16 teams, we have to eliminate 15,
then there has to be 15 matches.
Now with 224 nations participating,
we need to eliminate 223 teams in total.
Then naturally 223 matches have to be played.
This problem no longer requires us to
draw up such a complicated decision tree.
We use a one-to-one correspondence
to show that if there are n teams participating
then we need exactly n-1 elimination matches.
This one-to-one correspondence (injectivity)
demonstrates that brute-force enumeration is not always necessary.
We can use a degree of abstraction
to generate an ingenious idea,
which might make the problem wonderfully simple.