In this lesson, we shall learn
how to do well in combinatorics.
Essentially, the problem of how to count well.
Everyone knows the fundamental concept behind counting.
We simply count one by one.
In computing, there is a rather more elegant term for this:
enumeration - to highlight its enumerative nature,
we in fact call it
brute-force enumeration.
By its name, we can tell
that it's not an overly efficient method.
The thinking behind brute-force enumeration
is to count every single one of the possible solutions in turn.
In theory, it can solve all counting problems.
Of course, saying it works in theory
implies that it often fails in practice.
Let's see a simple example.
There's a football World Cup this year(2014).
Many students may encounter an awkward problem:
So many matches, right in the middle of exam season, what should I do?
Even if we refrain from watching the group-stage matches,
we can't bear to miss the elimination rounds. But how many of those are there?
We should plan out our time in advance.
So let's see,
In fact, we have to count how many elimination matches there are altogether.
Only 16 teams attending the World Cup
will advance to the knockout rounds.
The tournament system becomes very harsh:
single elimination, pitting two teams head-to-head,
with only the winner proceeding to the next round,
until the champion is decided.
How many matches have to be played in this process?
Let's think about it carefully first,
and then have a little quiz as following.