Welcome everyone, I am Prof. Yuchun Ma from the Department of Computing Science at Tsinghua University.
I am very glad to see everyone here£¬
so let's enjoy the beauty of combinatorics together.
Here at the Department of Computer Science at Tsinghua University,
Combinatorics is a fundamental course set at the graduate level.
But then we might ask,
since we have taken so many maths courses throughout our education,
why do we have yet another maths course at the graduate level?
We might not have heard of combinatorics before,
so if we want to find out what it is£¬
let's go online to have a look.
We can find the entry for combinatorics on Wikipedia.
The definition on Wikipedia is as follows:
"Combinatorics is a branch of mathematics..."
Right, so it's a branch of maths that deals with
problems of ordering and combining in discrete maths,
in particular methods of counting.
In fact the main application of combinatorics is for counting.
So what will we study?
Ordering(permutations) and combining (combination) problems from discrete maths.
So we might then wonder
if we've already studied undergraduate discrete maths,
would we have already covered everything to do with combinatorics£¿
We can have a look at a popular textbook.
Take this popular textbook on discrete maths.
Let's take a look
at what it contains.
We flip over to the contents page,
and discover that there are ten whole chapters.
Only in chapter 8
do we find some basics of combinatorial analysis,
in which there are a few simple counting algorithms,
and introductory concepts regarding permutations and combinations.
So we see that in discrete maths,
We only come across some very rudimentary combinatorics.
In this class however,
We shall really delve into combinatorics and related fields£¬
not least familiar concepts such as permutations and combinations.
We shall pay particular attention to a recursive counting algorithm
with wide-ranging applications in computing.
We'll also cover the inclusion-exclusion and the pigeonhole principles.
Finally, we shall investigate the very interesting topic of
counting the colourings of polygons,
using Burnside's lemma and the Polya enumeration theorem.
We can therefore see that combinatorics will involve
in-depth study of counting algorithms of discrete objects.
Next,
we shall take a brief overview of the history of mathematics.
Let us start from this graph:
what does the first illustration depict?
This is in fact
a calculating tool used by the people of the ancient Incan Empire.
We can say that mathematics has its roots in counting.
Then, after grasping the fundamental concept of counting,
we began to develop arithmetic,
elementary algebra, geometry, etc.,
until the appearance of variables in the 17th century.
From then on, mathematics moved into virgin territory,
and thus began the research of more advanced mathematical topics,
for example linear algebra, probability, etc.
The collective term given to these topics is mathematical analysis,
whose fertile grounds has produced
such mathematical greats as Leibniz, Euler, Gauss, etc.
Later, we discovered that mathematical analysis alone is insufficient.
So upon the foundations of mathematical analysis,
we developed topology, abstract algebra, group theory,
set theory, number theory etc.
These form the basis of modern mathematics.
With the development of computers,
people gradually found that combinatorics has become
a very important branch of modern mathematics,
for it directly impacts upon the theoretic development of informatics.
From our review of the development of mathematics,
We discover that the general development of mathematics
mirrors our own mathematical education.
There are many parallels to our personal experiences with mathematics.
When we are very young,
we begin counting from 1, 2, 3...
During our secondary education,
We'd already learned arithmetic and begin studying algebra and geometry.
Upon entering university,
we first encounter formal mathematical analysis:
we study advanced mathematics,
investigate linear algebra, etc.
But for modern mathematics,
we require more specialised tool and techniques.
For example we learn about graph theory and topology.
Combinatorics is specially relevant for computing
and forms part of the theoretical backbone for computer science.
Only after detailed study (perhaps at the graduate level),
can we hope to gain a more thorough understanding of algorithms.
To paraphrase the celebrated combinatorist Brualdi,
what is combinatorics really concerned with?
It investigates things that obey, to some degree, a rule or pattern.
Then we ask ourselves,
under such a rule,
do they exist,
how many distinct forms can they take,
can the algorithm be ¡®improved¡¯ in some way?
In combinatorics, then, we aim to answer three major questions.
First, the question of existence.
Second, the question of counting.
Third, the question of optimisation.
Since we now understand exactly what combinatorics is,
we shall, in the next lesson, explore in depth
the origins of combinatorics.