Let's first look at this photograph,
of this respectable old man.
His name is Thomas Tutte,
a very highly-regarded Canadian combinatorist.
But he is not only a titan in the world of combinatorics.
Recently findings reveal that
he in fact an important in the history of humanbeings.
We all know that during WWII,
Germany held a leading position in both hardware and encryption techniques.
They used the Lorenz cipher, reproduceable by the so-called "Tunny Machine".
This device held 12 mechanical wheels
enabling very elaborate encryption.
So the Germans believed that the code
generated by this machine was unbreakable.
What they didn't expect was the young Tutte
to accomplish an astonishing feat of ingenuity.
He only required just two messages sent by the Germans
to successfully break Tunny.
Thus we can see that
not even sophisticated devices employed by the Germans
are immune to combinatorics.
Let's now turn to the mobile phones we use every day:
we often need to unlock the screens.
But how safe is this process?
Here is the well-known iPhone.
Its passcode is very simple, comprising only four digits.
So is this method perhaps not as secure
as we would like?
Do Android phones employ a superior technique?
Next we'll watch a short video
It seems that even Professor Du can not break the code.
But can Professor Tutte
help us with the passcode problem, using combinatorics?
Whether your mobile is secure or not can only be determined by calculation.
Next we'll see
How to calculate how many passcode combinations there are in total.
This is the Android "screen locked" interface.
We can clearly see that
We can use different paths to set different passcodes.
Simply put, we are basically just
choosing several numbers from these nine.
If you set a one- or two- digit passcode, it is far too easy to break.
So Android passcodes should at least use 4 digits.
What is the maximum number of digits you can use?
Only 9, for you can only join up a maximum of 9 dots.
If we ignore the positions of those dots,
let's calculate how many possibilities there are altogether.
If we set a four-digit passcode,
if we pick 4 digits from nine, there are P(9,4) possibilities.
Picking 5 gives P(9,5) possibilities... all the way up to P(9,9).
The sum of all these numbers is 985824.
But this way of calculation does not take into account
the effects of ordering and position when linking up dots.
For example, let's observe the fact that
in an interface such as this,
When we go from 1 to 3 we have to pass through 2.
So if I set the passcode to be 1 and then 3,
then this is an infeasible passcode.
So we see that, because in the prior calculation
we did not consider restraints posed by positioning,
we will also have counted some infeasible passcodes.
So how many feasible passcodes are there altogether?
One possible approach:
we can count up all the infeasible passcodes; subtracting this number
from the total gives the number of the logical passcodes.
So from this we can see,
We can calculate all the possibilities,
exclude the infeasible solutions,